Bill Sweeney

Full Stack Web Developer

Github: https://github.com/panamabilly

LinkedIN: www.linkedin.com/in/billsweeney85

Experienced engineering professional with proven track record of providing sound engineering solutions, desiring to expand my horizons to full stack web development, which has a passion for computers and is highly focused on learning technologies, moving projects forward and also has the ability to communicate, collaborate with others as well as has the ability to complete highly technical projects with great attention to detail.

Austin Metropolitan Area Round Rock, TX 78681 (801) 540-8943 billsweeney85@gmail.com

EXPERIENCE

General Assembly, Remote — *Software Engineering Immersive Student*

NOVEMBER 2011 - FEBRUARY 2022

Completed 12-week, 500+ hour training program focused in Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, MongoDB, SQL, Python, and covered fundamental Computer Science topics. Fascinated with the material learned during the course and am excited about expanding my knowledge and starting a career in Tech. I enjoyed launching my first application in gitHub after working on it diligently for a few days.

Watearth Inc, Austin, TX — *Water Resources Engineer*

OCTOBER 2019 - OCTOBER 2021

Worked as a project engineer and completed a FEMA Floodplain Map Revision for Creekside Hills Subdivision in Copperas Cove, TX . A 2-year water resource project budgeted roughly at 500K that consisted of technical hydraulic and hydrologlic models (H&H) and a detailed engineering report supporting the modeling effort and change of floodplain inundation extents. Collaborated with GIS professionals to produce high quality floodplain maps. My contribution resulted in FEMA approval of the new inundation extents. Also, provided technical engineering assistance involving modeling, authored several technical reports, led technical training, updated project management tasks, conducted desktop studies in various other water resource engineering projects. Led weekly progress meeting for the company.

Texas Commission on Environmental Quality, Austin, TX — Dam Safety Engineering Specialist III

AUGUST 2013- MAY 2019

Worked as dam safety engineer and reviewed detailed design plans, emergency action plans and hydrologic and hydraulic technical documents in a team based environment. Performed near 100 dam safety inspections as primary or secondary inspector and reviewed engineering reports and models submitted to the State for approval.

SKILLS

Problem Solver
Detail Oriented
Productive in High Pressure
Environments
Collaborative Spirit
Active Communicator
Optimizes Time Efficiently

CERTIFICATIONS

Texas EIT

DEPLOYMENT

Git.GitHub. Command Line

LANGUAGES

HTML5, CSS, JavaScript, Python, Spanish

RUNTIME ENVIRONMENTS

Node

FRAMEWORKS

Express, Dango

DATABASE SERVICES

SQL, MongoDB

EDUCATION

General Assembly, Remote — *Software Engineering Immersive Graduate*

NOVEMBER 2011 - FEBRUARY 2022

Completed 2-week , 500+ hour training program which covered the foundations of Computer Science and Full Stack Web Development. The program focused on the technologies listed in my experience section and shown the project section below.

University of Utah, Salt Lake City, UT — *B.S in Civil and Environmental Engineering*

DECEMBER 2009 - MAY 2013

Graduated from ABET accredited university focusing in fundamentals of Civil and Environmental Engineering. My focus was in Water Resources, Hydrology and Environmental Engineering. Completed upper division coursework in ArcGIS and Project Management. The GIS course sparked my interest in databases and GIS.

PROJECTS

Simon LightBoard Game — *HTML, CSS and JavaScript Based Project*

Developed an application in a week using Javascript fundamentals that consisted of a game to be deployed online. I chose Simon which is a memory game of lights where the player has to repeat a light pattern given by the Simon board. Enjoyed the struggle and the success of coding the logic for the computer code to check whether the light sequence matches the player entered sequence.

Project 2 — React Based Project

Developed an application using Javascript fundamentals that consisted of a game to be deployed online. Simon which is a memory game of lights where the player has to follow a pattern given by the Simon board. I enjoyed the challenge of coding the logic for the computer code to check whether the light sequence matches the player sequence.

Project 3 — Express Based Project

My project was to develop an application using Javascript fundamentals that consisted of a game to be deployed online. I chose Simon which is a memory game of lights where the player has to follow a pattern given by the Simon board . The player wins after a certain amount of rounds are completed.

Project 4 — Python Based Project

My project was to develop an application using Javascript fundamentals that consisted of a game to be deployed online. I chose Simon which is a memory game of lights where the player has to follow a pattern given by the Simon board . The player wins after a certain amount of rounds are completed.